New York State Common Cause; Records apap059
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
New York State Common Cause Records
1972-1987
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap059
7 cubic ft.
The records of New York State Common Cause document campaigns against political action committees, election reform, civil service reform, and accountability issues.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by New York State Common Cause on 29 April 1988.
Administrative History
New York State Common Cause (NYSCC), a state chapter of Common Cause, was founded in 1973 as a grassroots organization to promote an open and accountable legislative process. NYSCC advocates the participation of all members of society in the government process as a means to ensure that lawmakers will be responsible for their legislative decisions. To achieve its goals, NYSCC actively lobbies for and against legislation at the state level.
The function of the Executive Committee is to develop policy, but the Governing Board must approve these recommendations before these become the actual policy of NYSCC. The Executive Director, who is the public representative of NYSCC, is accountable to the Governing Board and implements policies approved by the Board. The Chairman of the Board, an unpaid member elected to this post, is the chief officer of NYSCC. With the exception of the director and some office help, NYSCC is staffed by volunteers whose major duties are to lobby legislators. NYSCC also manages an internship program which uses volunteers to generate reports, perform surveys, carry on a dialogue with lawmakers, and generally to perform the duties of a staff member.
In 1988, after having maintained two offices, one in New York City and a head office in Albany, NYSCC closed its Albany office and moved all operations to New York City, the center of its financial and volunteer support.
Scope and Contents
The records of New York State Common Cause span the years 1972 through 1987. Since NYSCC is an organization that campaigns for accountability in government, its records would be of interest to researchers of campaigns against political action committees (PACs), 1980-86; election reform, 1977-83; civil service reform, 1978-80; and accountability issues such as Sunset Law reform, 1976-78.
A major issue of concern to NYSCC has been the contribution political action committees make to election campaigns. Studies conducted by NYSCC determined the amount of money donated to individual candidates by PACs. Another important issue documented in the records of NYSCC are several reports on the inequality of the electoral campaign system, specifically on the advantage that incumbent candidates hold in most elections.
As an early advocate and, later, as a prominent member of the New York Temporary State Commission on Lobbying, NYSCC retained ample documentation of that body, including minutes, correspondence and the records of legal challenges to the commission such as "Hobday, et al., v. the New York Temporary State Commission on Regulation of Lobbying." Other records relating to lobbying in New York State include an analysis of how agencies retained agency logs (registers of lobbyists who have approached state agencies), lobbying registration forms that NYSCCC filed with the state, and studies by NYSCC on the money spent on lobbying by business interests.
Of particular note for researchers should be the interviews with politicians contained in the OUTS (Open Up the System) surveys that NYSCC conducted from 1976 to 1980 on such issues as legislative reform, PAC regulation, lobbying reform, conflict of interest in the legislature, and the public financing of campaigns. Politicians surveyed include such prominent individuals as Senator Warren Anderson. The OUTS Surveys reveal the positions of senators and assembly persons on specific bills before the legislature as well as their attitudes toward the wider issues concerning the access to and structure of government.
Arrangement of the Collection
Series 1 - Subject Files. 1976-1987. 3 cubic feet. Arranged alphabetically.
Series 2: Issues Files. 1976-87. 3 cubic feet. Arranged alphabetically.
Series 3: Lobbying Files. 1976-87. 0.5 cubic feet. Arranged alphabetically.
Series 4: OUTS (Open Up The System). 1976-80. 0.5 cubic feet. Arranged alphabetically.
This collection is arranged into four series.
Social Activists and Public Advocates; Lobbying--Law and legislation; Political action committees--Law and legislation; Political action committees--United States; Elections--New York (State); Elections--New York (State)--New York; Albany (N.Y.); New York (State); Newsletters; Correspondence; Administrative records; Minutes; Programs (documents); New York State Common Cause
- Administrative, 1976-1987; 1; 3 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes correspondence, general administrative files, reports from the director to the Executive Board, General Board minutes, memoranda and agendas, executive board agendas, budgets, news releases and clippings on specific topics such as political action committees (PACs) (1980-86), election reform (1977-83), civil service reform (1978-80), and the Sunset Law (1976-78). The series also includes correspondence with the national Common Cause regarding issues the local chapters should address.
  - Activist: The Common Cause, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 1)
  - Activist: New York State Common Cause, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 2)
  - Advantage Incumbent, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 3)
  - Budget for 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 4)
  - Budget for 1980, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 5)
  - Budget for 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 6)
  - Budget for 1983, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 7)
  - Budget for 1985, 1983-1985 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 8)
  - Budgets--National, 1979-1980; 1983-1985 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 9)
  - Budgets--National, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 10)
  - Campaign '82--Activist Registration Forms and Workshop Training Manual, 1982 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 11)
  - Certification of Delegates to the Governing Board, 1983 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 12)
  - Certification of Delegates to the Governing Board, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 13)
  - Conference Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 14)
  - The Contribution Connection...State Legislative Chairs, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 15)
  - Coolfont Conference (Staff Training Conference), 1980 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1982 January-June (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1982 July-December (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1983 June-December (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1983 January-May (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1984 January-December (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 23)
  - Correspondence--Commercial Mailing, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 24)
  - Correspondence--National, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 25)
  - Correspondence--National, 1981-1984 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 26)
  - Correspondence--National, 1985-1987 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 27)
  - Correspondence--Rebuttal to a Letter to the Editor, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Administrative), Folder 28)
  - Elections to Governing Board, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 1)
  - Expense Reports, 1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 2)
  - Fundraising--"Give a Gift of Common Cause" Campaign, 1983 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 3)
  - Fundraising--Spring Appeal, 1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 4)
  - Fundraising--Spring Appeal, 1985. (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 5)
  - Governing Board and Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 6)
  - Governing Board ;amp Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1979 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 7)
  - Governing Board ;amp Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 8)
  - Governing Board ;amp Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1981 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 9)
  - Governing Board ;amp Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1982 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 10)
  - Governing Board ;amp Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1983 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 11)
  - Governing Board ;amp Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1984 January-June (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 12)
  - Governing Board ;amp Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1984 July-December (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 13)
  - Governing Board ;amp Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1985 January-July (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 14)
  - Governing Board ;amp Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1985 August-Decmber (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 15)
  - How They Stand, 1982 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 16)
  - Internships in Fall 1982 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 17)
  - Internships in Spring 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 18)
  - Internships in Spring 1983, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 19)
  - Internships in Fall 1983 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 20)
  - Internships in Spring 1984, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 21)
  - Internships in Spring 1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 22)
  - Internships in Spring 1985, 1984-1985 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 23)
  - Internships with National, 1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 24)
  - Issues Committee, 1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 25)
  - Issues--Recommendations and Reports, 1983-1985 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 26)
  - Leases, 1978-1983 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 27)
  - Lobbying Kit, 1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 28)
  - Lobbying Kits for Public Financing, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 29)
  - Memoranda, 1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 30)
  - National Program Activities, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 31)
  - New York State Common Cause, 1979-1987 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 32)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 33)
  - Personnel File for Paul Elisha, 1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 34)
  - Press Releases, 1975; 1978-1979 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 35)
  - Press Releases, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 36)
  - Recruitment Manual--Make a Difference, 1986 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 37)
  - Recruitment--Sample Speech, 1981 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 38)
  - Reorganization Proposals for National Common Cause, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (1-Administrative), Folder 39)
  - Reorganization Proposals for National Common Cause, 1980-1982 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 1)
  - Reorganization Proposals for New York State Common Cause, 1979 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 2)
  - Reports on Issues (Folder 1), 1980 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 3)
  - Reports on Issues (Folder 2), 1980 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 4)
  - Reports on Issues (Folder 1), 1981 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 5)
  - Reports on Issues (Folder 2), 1981 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 6)
  - Reports on Issues (Folder 1), 1982 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 7)
  - Reports on Issues (Folder 2), 1982 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 8)
  - Reports on Issues (Folder 1), 1983 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 9)
  - Reports on Issues (Folder 2), 1983 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 10)
  - Reports on Issues, 1984 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 11)
  - Reports on Issues (Folder I), 1985 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 12)
  - Reports on Issues (Folder II), 1985 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 13)
  - Revenue and Expenses, 1984 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 14)
  - Revenue and Expenses, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 15)
  - Spring Convention, 1980-1984 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 16)
  - Spring Convention, 1984 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 17)
  - Staff Training Orientation, 1983-1984 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 18)
  - State Personnel Manual, 1983 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 19)
  - Sweepstakes, 1979/1986 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 20)
  - Update, 1976-82, 84-87., 1976-1982; 1984-1987 (Box 3 (1-Administrative), Folder 21)
- Issues, 1976-1987; 2; 3 cubic ft.
  This series includes clippings and background files on topics and issues addressed by Common Cause. Some of the issues included are bottle bill legislation (1978-84), civil service reform (1977-80), PAC regulation (1980-86), campaign financing (1977-83), legislative reform (1977-83), and milk deregulation (1981-83). Also included are reports and studies generated to support specific issues.
  - Access to Information, 1983-1984 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 1)
  - Access to Information--Fees, 1984 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 2)
  - AIDS, 1984 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 3)
  - Bank Study, 1980 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 4)
  - Bottle Bill, 1978-1982 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 5)
  - Bottle Bill, 1980 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 6)
  - Bottle Bill, 1981 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 7)
  - Bottle Bill, 1980-1984 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 8)
  - Bottle Bill--Additional Research, 1980-1981 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 9)
  - Bottle Bill--Background Information, 1978-1982 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 10)
  - Bottle Bill--Campaign Gifts by Opponents to Bill, 1981 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 11)
  - Bottle Bill--Newspaper Clippings, 1984 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 12)
  - Bottle Bill--Opposition, 1979-1981 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 13)
  - Bottle Bill--Opposition, 1982 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 14)
  - Budgets for New York State, 1982-1985 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 15)
  - Cable Television Regulation, 1980-1982 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 16)
  - Cable Television Regulation, 1981-1982 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 17)
  - Campaign Financing, 1972; 1978 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 18)
  - Campaign Financing, 1978 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 19)
  - Campaign Financing, 1977-1979 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 20)
  - Campaign Financing, 1980-1981; 1983 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 21)
  - Campaign Financing--1978 Gubernatorial Race, 1980 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 22)
  - Campaign Financing--Large Contributions in New York's 1978 Race for Governor, 1980 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 23)
  - Campaign Financing--New Jersey and California, 1983 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 24)
  - Campaign Financing--Special Interest Contributions, 1980 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 25)
  - Campaign Spending--Assets ;amp Liabilities, 1981 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 26)
  - Campaign Spending--Big Spenders, 1982 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 27)
  - Campaign Spending--Big Spenders (Folder I), 1983 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 28)
  - Campaign Spending--Big Spenders (Folder II), 1983 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 29)
  - Campaign Spending--Outstanding Loans, 1980 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 30)
  - Campaign Spending--Senate Campaign of 1982, 1980, 1983. (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 31)
  - Campaign Spending in New York Legislative Races, 1982 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 32)
  - Campaign Spending Limits, 1978 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 33)
  - Campaign 1982--Issues (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 34)
  - Candidates' Positions--Exposure `86, 1986 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 35)
  - Citizens Utility Board, 1983-1984 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 36)
  - Citizens Utility Board, 1984-1985 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 37)
  - Civil Service Reform, 1978 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 38)
  - Civil Service Reform, 1979 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 39)
  - Civil Service Reform (Folder I), 1980 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 40)
  - Civil Service Reform (Folder II), 1980 (Box 4 (2-Issues), Folder 41)
  - Civil Service Reform--Additional Research, 1980 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 1)
  - Civil Service Reform--Annual Report of Department of Civil Service and Civil Service Commission, 1979 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 2)
  - Civil Service Reform--Annual Report of Department of Civil Service and Civil Service Commission, 1980 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 3)
  - Civil Service Reform--Federal, 1978-1979 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 4)
  - Civil Service Reform--Improving Management of the Public Work Force, 1978 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 5)
  - Civil Service Reform--Mayor Edward Koch's Proposals, 1979 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 6)
  - Civil Service Reform--A Model Public Personnel Administration Law, circa 1980 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 7)
  - Civil Service Reform--Newspaper Clippings, 1977-1980 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 8)
  - Civil Service Reform--Newspaper Clippings, 1980 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 9)
  - Civil Service Reform--Public Hearings, 1980 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 10)
  - Civil Service Reform--"Red Tape and Civil Service, circa 1980 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 11)
  - Civil Service Reform--Report with Recommendations on the Improvement of Personnel Management, 1977 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 12)
  - Civil Service Reform--Toward Improvement of Service to the Public, 1978 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 13)
  - Conference Committees, 1977 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 14)
  - Congressional Campaign Finance Reform Act, 1984 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 15)
  - Constitutional Revision--New York State, 1976-1977 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 16)
  - Court Reform (Folder 1-3), 1979-1981 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 17-19)
  - Defense Spending, 1984 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 20)
  - District of Columbia Voting Rights, 1983-1985 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 21)
  - Energy Conservation, 1981-1985 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 22)
  - Environmental Protection, 1983-1986 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 23)
  - Equal Rights Amendment for New York State, 1975 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 24)
  - Equal Rights Amendment for the United States, 1975-1979 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 25)
  - Experience Curve, 1985 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 26)
  - Financial Disclosure Statements by State Legislators, 1972 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 27)
  - Gubernatorial Candidates for 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 28)
  - Gubernatorial Race--Carey, 1974 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 29)
  - Hazardous Waste--Superfund, 1985 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 30)
  - Home Energy Audit--Fees, 1981 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 31)
  - Industrial Trade Secrets, 1978; 1981 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 32)
  - Issue Evaluations and Recommendations, 1984 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 33)
  - Legislative Bills, 1987 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 34)
  - Legislative Reform--Bill, 1976-1978 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 35)
  - Legislative Reform--New York State Coalition for Legislative Reform, 1972-1975 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 36)
  - Legislative Reform--Newspaper Clippings, 1975-1978 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 37)
  - Legislative Reform--Proposals, 1977 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 38)
  - Legislative Reform--Survey, 1977 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 39)
  - Legislative Reform--Survey Results, 1978 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 40)
  - Lulus--Supplements to Salaries and Expense Allowances for Legislators, 1976-1980 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 41)
  - Milk--Deregulation, 1981-1983 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 42)
  - National Issues (Folder 1-2), 1984 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 43-44)
  - New York State Budget, 1984 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 45)
  - New York State Legislature, 1984 (Box 5 (2-Issues), Folder 46)
  - Nuclear Arms, 1982 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 1)
  - Nuclear Freeze, 1983 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 2)
  - Open Government, 1981 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 3)
  - Personal Privacy Protection, 1980 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 4)
  - Plant Relocation, 1983 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 5)
  - Political Action Committees, 1980 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 6)
  - Political Action Committees, 1981 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 7)
  - Political Action Committees, 1984 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 8)
  - Political Action Committees, 1985-1986 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 9)
  - Political Action Committees Administered by Corporations, 1981 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 10)
  - Political Action Committees--Financial Disclosure, 1981 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 11)
  - Political Action Committees--"People Against PACs March on Wall Street,", 1983 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 12)
  - Political Reform Act of 1974--California, 1977, 1980. (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 13)
  - Public Sector Collective Bargaining, 1979 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 14)
  - Reconstituted Milk Regulation, 1980 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 15)
  - Redistricting, 1981-1982 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 16)
  - Redistricting--Litigation, 1982 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 17)
  - Reviving Competition in New York State Elections, 1984 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 18)
  - Senate Rules Reform, 1984 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 19)
  - Senate Standing Committee on Civil Service and Pensions--Public Hearing, 8 Aug 1979 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 20)
  - Senate Standing Committee on Civil Service and Pensions--Public Hearing, 10 Sep 1979 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 21)
  - Sex-Segregated Career Ladders in New York State Government Employment, 1980 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 22)
  - Special Interest Rollcall, 1980 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 23)
  - State Issues, 1983-1984 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 24)
  - State Issues, 1984 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 25)
  - State Issues--Approved, 1983-1987 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 26)
  - State of the State Address by Governor Cuomo, 1983-1985 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 27)
  - State Special Interest Project, 1980-1981 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 28)
  - Sunset Laws, 1977-1978 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 29)
  - Sunset Laws--New York State, 1976-1977 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 30)
  - Tax Expenditures, 1984 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 31)
  - Tax Reform (Folder 1 and 2), 1976-1982 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 32-33)
  - Tax Reform, 1983-1985 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 34)
  - Television Editorials, 1984 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 35)
  - Toxic Tort Legislation, 1985-1986 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 36)
  - Voting Records of Legislators, 1982 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 37)
  - Westway Trade-In, 1981-1984 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 38)
  - Whistleblowers, 1984 (Box 6 (2-Issues), Folder 39)
- Lobbying Files, 1976-1987; 3; 0.5 cubic ft.
  The series consists mainly of correspondence and meeting minutes of the New York Temporary State Lobbying Commission regarding lobbying regulations and documentation on two court cases involving the commission, the most prominent being "Hobday, et al., v. the New York Temporary State Commission on Regulation of Lobbying." As an early advocate of the creation of the Lobbying Commission, NYSCC was represented on the commission by its director. The series also contains an analysis of New York State government agency logs, NYSCC lobbying registration forms, lobbying reports and studies on the amount of money spent on lobbying by business interests. New York State Common Cause
  - Agency Logs--Analysis of Section 166 of the Executive Law of New York State, 1981-1982 (Box 6 (3-Lobbying Files), Folder 40)
  - Allocation Statistics--Lobbyists in 1980, 1981 (Box 6 (3-Lobbying Files), Folder 41)
  - Commission on Independent Colleges and Universities v. New York Temporary State Commission on Regulation of Lobbying, 1980-1982 (Box 6 (3-Lobbying Files), Folder 42)
  - Correspondence with Lobbyists, 1980-1981 (Box 6 (3-Lobbying Files), Folder 43)
  - District Maps, 1978 (Box 6 (3-Lobbying Files), Folder 44)
  - Downstate Lobbying Priorities, 1981 (Box 6 (3-Lobbying Files), Folder 45)
  - Expenditures by Clients of Lobbyists in 1980, circa 1980 (Box 6 (3-Lobbying Files), Folder 46)
  - Expenditures by Utility Companies on Lobbying, 1981 (Box 6 (3-Lobbying Files), Folder 47)